https://www.primarygames.com/privacy.php

Effective: September 15, 2020
PrimaryGames.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. PrimaryGames is intended to provide fun and educational resources for kids and teens to use under the guidance of their parents and teachers. As required by The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), we provide this privacy policy to inform parents and legal guardians (collectively, “Parents”) about our privacy practices on our site www.primarygames.com.
Information Automatically Logged
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information. We also gather other information automatically and store it in log files, such information may include browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We use this information to help us design a website that is targeted to the interests of our visitors. We do link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.
Tracking Technologies and Cookies
Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by PrimaryGames and our marketing, affiliates and analytics partners. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
Advertisers
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. In response to the new COPPA rules, PrimaryGames.com has opted out of behaviorally targeted ads from all of our advertising networks, and instead only shows contextually-based ads or other carefully-selected ads which are not based on a user's browsing behavior.
We have asked all of our advertising networks to turn off all behaviorally targeted ads that would track a user or attempt to create a profile on any of our users. We have also alerted our advertising agencies that a portion of our audience is "under 13" and that they need to adhere to all COPPA rules and regulations. PrimaryGames does not run behaviorally targeted ads, but, if you want to opt out of these on other websites that do, you can opt out here: http://www.iab.net/privacymatters/
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique “cookie” or web beacon on your browser.
You can view the privacy policies for each ad company by following the links below:
Google Adsense: https://www.google.com/privacy.html
CPMStar: http://www.cpmstar.com/privacyPolicy.html
Amazon: http://www.amazon.com/privacy
Driver Digital: http://www.driverdigital.com/privacy
BatteryPOP: http://www.batterypop.com/privacy-policy
SuperAwesome: http://www.superawesome.tv/privacy_policy/
PlayWire: http://playwiremedia.com/privacy/
Analytics
PrimaryGames.com uses third-party analytics software to provide us with information regarding the usage of the Website. The information we receive from such third-party analytics software is not Personal Information attributable to any user but rather information that is aggregated by the software so that we can track such things as how many users we have of the Website on a daily, weekly or monthly basis, what Website content or features our users are frequenting and the general geographic locations of our users.
To opt-out from this type of tracking, please use the links below:
Google Analytics: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
Local Storage HTML5/LSO
We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here:
https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/
External Links
This site contains links to other sites. PrimaryGames.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every site that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies only to the information collected on this Site.
Security
The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.
No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.
Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Children's Guidelines
We care about children and understand that they have special privacy needs. Therefore, we have adopted the following privacy policy regarding children:
We will NOT collect, use, or distribute to third parties personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent.
When verifiable parental consent is not obtained, the virtual worlds we partner with will only use the online contact information (such as email) to:
Respond directly to the child's request on a one-time basis and not use that information to re-contact the child for other purposes. Once we have responded to such request we will delete the information provided immediately.
Request the name or online contact information of a parent for the purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing parental notification.
Respond more than once directly to a specific request from a child (such as in the case where a child requests a newsletter subscription) and not used to re-contact the child for other purposes. We will use our best efforts to provide parental notification, which will include the nature and intended use as well as an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity.
We will provide you with a description of the specific types of a personally identifiable information collected on the site, for instance when you send a post card, we may collect your name, email address and recipient’s name and email address. We do not store this information for any purpose.
E-Cards and Postcards
We hope you and your children enjoy our E-cards together. The information you submit is for your card only. It appears on your computer screen for your use and is deleted when the email card activity is completed. Email cards sent via e-mail to your selected recipient(s) are automatically deleted from our files 21 days after you send them. You must be 13 years or older to submit information. Parents, please help your child fill out the postcard forms. When sending a postcard for the first time, we require users to specify for their age. Any users who identify themselves as under 13 will be blocked from using our postcard service. We use persistent cookies to remember whether or not the user is over the age of 13.
Social Media (Features) and Widgets
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. The only information we collect from you prior to allowing your use of the tell a friend feature that is ran by a third party social media feature is your age to determine whether or not you are able to use this feature.
Third Party Sharing
We will share your personal information only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.
We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as providing customer support or content management. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.
If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified by prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
Access to Personal Information
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at privacy@primarygames.com.
We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.
Data Retention
We will retain your information as needed to provide you services. If you wish to request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at the email address provided above.
We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Age Restricted Activities
Most of the activities and features on PrimaryGames.com are able to be enjoyed by all ages. There a minor few that require the user to be 13 years or older. On these pages, we ask users to specify their age. Any users who identify themselves as under 13 will be redirected to another age appropriate page. We use cookies to remember whether or not the user is over the age of 13 in order to tailor their experience while using PrimaryGames.com.
Virtual Worlds
We feature several Virtual Worlds for children from third-party partner web sites on PrimaryGames.com. All information collected while interacting with each world is collected by the Company that owns and maintains that particular world. Please refer to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions for each individual Virtual World. We have provided links to each world's Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions on the game's web page. Questions regarding each world should be directed to the appropriate party and contact links for each game can be found on the game's web page.
Moshi Monsters
Privacy Policy
Contact
Club Penguin
Privacy Policy
Contact
Fantage
Privacy Policy
Contact
PBS KIDS PLAY!
Privacy Policy
Contact
Yoobot vs YooNot
Privacy Policy
Contact
WebbliWorld
Privacy Policy
Contact
Changes in this Privacy Policy
We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
If we make material changes to how we use personal information collected from children under 13, we will notify parents by e-mail (if possible), or by means of a notice on this Site in order to obtain verifiable consent for the new uses of the child's personal information.
Contacting the Web Site
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:
PrimaryGames, Inc.
8947 Hollymeade Drive
Lorton, VA 22079
(703) 493-8568
privacy@primarygames.com
About Us
RSS
Submit Games
Tell a Friend
PRIVACY
Privacy Policy at PrimaryGamesPlay free online games featuring the best action, adventure, sports, racing, puzzle and learning games! Make new friends and create your own world in one of the many free virtual worlds on PrimaryGames. All games are safe and free to play online.Are you looking for unblocked games? PrimaryGames is the fun place to learn and play! Play cool games, math games, reading games, girl games, puzzles, sports games, print coloring pages, read online storybooks, and hang out with friends while playing one of the many virtual worlds found on PrimaryGames. All games are free to play and new content is added every week. We work hard to bring you best gaming content on the web! Each game is reviewed to ensure that is is safe for all ages. With over 1,000 flash game titles and growing we have the largest collection of cool games online. Whether you like Adventure or Racing, Classic Arcade or Action, Strategy Puzzles or Dress Up games, we have something for you!
Holidays at PrimaryGamesPrimaryGames has a large collection of holiday games, crafts, coloring pages, postcards and stationery for the following holidays: Christmas, Halloween, Easter, Valentine's Day, St. Patrick's Day, Thanksgiving, Presidents' Day, Hanukkah, New Year's Eve and more. Every day is a day to celebrate!Learning at PrimaryGamesCalling all Teachers! Visit our Curriculum Guide to find games and activities to meet your classroom's curriculum needs for Math, Science, Language Arts, and Social Studies. This quick guide contains content descriptions and grade level suggestions for all of the educational activities on PrimaryGames.
More Cool Sites
COOL GAMES
PrimaryGames
TEENS
teenPG
GagaGirl Games
GAMES
AllStar Sports Games
© 2020 PrimaryGames, Inc. All rights reserved.
Link to Us
Report an Ad
HTML5 Games
View Full Desktop SiteView Mobile Site
